this problem asks us to
iterate through an array and print each
index
and value in that array and we're going
to use the
each with index method to accomplish
this
so we've already got an array here
called top 5
games and this is the array that we're
going to invoke the each with index
method on
now when you call each on an array
each element of that array is going to
be passed as an argument to the block
when using each with index both the
element
and its index will be passed to the
block
so we'll define these block parameters
with appropriate names
first the element itself will be passed
and this second argument will be the
index
so we'll name that parameter accordingly
now within our block we know we want to
output both the
element and the index so we'll invoke
put us
and use string interpolation here
let's number our list of games so first
we'll
output the index
and then the game
now let's run our code and take a look
at our output
so this looks pretty good we've got our
five games listed
and each index is listed as well but our
output looks a little bit
odd here we number our games from 0 to 4
rather than from 1 to 5. of course
that's because
array indexes are 0 based so
the index of the first element will be 0
and the index of the last element will
be one less
than the size of that array in this case
four
since this looks a little bit odd let's
go back to our code
instead of numbering our games just by
the index
let's add one to that index and now
we'll expect that the output will be
numbered one to five
running our code again that's what we
see
you